# CHANDRADEEP POKHARIYA

+91 7895849847 ♦ chandradeep.pokhariya@research.iiit.ac.in ♦ website

#### **SUMMARY**

I am currently a Senior Project Scientist under the guidance of Dr. Rahul Narain at IIT Delhi, focusing on Differentiable Cloth Simulation. I previously earned my M.S. (Research) degree at IIIT Hyderabad, where I was advised by Dr. Avinash Sharma at the CVIT Lab and Dr. Srinath Sridhar at the Brown Visual Computing Lab.

My research experience spans diverse areas, including neural fields, hand-object grasp capture, textured cloth and human body reconstruction, neural surface parameterization, and physics simulation. I am grateful that some of these research projects have also been converted to publications in peer-reviewed conferences and journals.

At present, my primary research interests revolve around physics-based simulation and hand-object manipulation.

#### **EDUCATION**

MS by Research in Computer Science and Engineering (CGPA 9.5/10.0) January 2022 - July 2024 International Institute of Information Technology, Hyderabad, India.

(Courses Taken: - Topics in Applied Optimization - Topics in Deep Learning - Statistical Methods in AI - Advanced Graphics & AR/VR - Computer Vision)

#### RESEARCH PUBLICATIONS

Manas Chaudhary, C Pokhariya, A P Rathore, A Chakraborty, R Narain Towards Generalized Position-Based Dynamics, Under Evaluation

C Pokhariya, I Shah\*, A Xing\*, Z Li, K Chen, A Sharma, S Sridhar MANUS: Markerless Hand-Object Grasp Capture using Articulated 3D Gaussians, CVPR'24

C Lu\*, P Zhou\*, A Xing\*, C Pokhariya, A Dey, I Shah, R Mavidipalli, D Hu, A Comport, K Chen, S Sridhar DiVA-360: The Dynamic Visuo-Audio Dataset for Immersive Neural Fields. CVPR'24 Highlight

C Pokhariya\*, S Naik\*, A Srivastava, A Sharma Discretization-Agnostic Deep Self-Supervised 3D Surface Parameterization, accepted at SIGGRAPH-Asia'22, Technical Communications

A Srivastava, C Pokhariya, SS Jinka, A Sharma xCloth: Extracting Template-free Textured 3D Clothes from a Monocular Image, accepted at ACM Multimedia'22

SS Jinka, A Srivastava, C Pokhariya, A Sharma, PJ Narayanan SHARP: Shape Aware Reconstruction of People in Loose Clothing., accepted at IJCV (International Journal of Computer Vision), November 2021.

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

# Visiting Research Fellow at Brown IVL (Brown University)

July 2023 - Nov 2023

- · Visited beautiful Providence to work with Dr Srinath Sridhar on accurate contact capture from hand-object grasp videos.
- · Self-supervised learning of grasping field for generative grasp synthesis of hands.

# Research Assistant at CVIT lab (IIIT Hyderabad).

May 2021 - Present

- · Neural UV parameterization which attempts to generalize the parameterization over category specific classes.
- · Co-Authored the ACMMM'22 work xCloth on textured garment digitzation from monocular images.
- · Worked on the problem of 3D reconstruction of people in loose clothing, which resulted in the SHARP.

<sup>\*</sup> refers to equal contribution.

#### FUN PROJECTS

# Geometry Processing

- · Implementation of geometry processing algorithms from scratch.
- · Implemented the "Laplacian Surface Editing algorithm" from scratch to deform the mesh based on anchor points.
- · Implemented "Learning Mesh-Based Simulation with Graph Networks" as a part of course project.

## **HPG 2022 Student Competition**

- · HPG provided an implementation of a raytracer on shadertoy. The goal was to achieve the highest possible quality compared to a brute-force reference (100k samples per pixel) without a significant performance cost.
- · Our implementation of raytracer was unbiased and ranked 4th by HPG.

#### **ACTIVITIES**

Attended the Symposium on Geometry Processing 2024 conference at MIT Boston.

Presented our project MANUS & Diva360 at CVPR'24 in Seattle.

Served as a reviewer for ACMMM'23, CVPR'24, SIGGRAPH'24, and ECCV'24 conferences.

Selected as one of 250 attendees from across India for Google Research Week'23 in Bengaluru.

2023

# REFERENCES

## Dr. Rahul Narain

Assistant Professor IIT Delhi

(Research collaborator and mentor)

#### Dr. Srinath Sridhar

Assistant Professor & P.I of the Interactive 3D Vision & Learning Lab (IVL)

Brown University

(Research collaborator and master thesis co-advisor)

#### Dr. Avinash Sharma

Assistant Professor

International Institute of Information Technology Hyderabad

(Master thesis advisor and project quide)